<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WaDL</title>
    <link>https://www.richpauloo.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.richpauloo.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>WaDL</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>WAter Data Lab © 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 12:22:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.richpauloo.com/img/sharing.png</url>
      <title>WaDL</title>
      <link>https://www.richpauloo.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pub1</title>
      <link>https://www.richpauloo.com/publication/pub1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 12:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.richpauloo.com/publication/pub1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;adf sadf&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pub2</title>
      <link>https://www.richpauloo.com/publication/pub2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 12:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.richpauloo.com/publication/pub2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>low cost sensor networks</title>
      <link>https://www.richpauloo.com/project/lcsn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.richpauloo.com/project/lcsn/</guid>
      <description>


  











&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://www.richpauloo.com/img/watergrid_mockup.png&#34; &gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.richpauloo.com/img/watergrid_mockup.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Custom solutions for automated, real-time streaming of environmental data from sensor-networks deployed in the field, directly to the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These cloud-based, lightweight, scalable groundwater observatory dashboards are easily applied to any &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/w12041066&#34;&gt;low cost sensor network&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This solutions is well suited for groundwater monitoring to support implementation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://water.ca.gov/Programs/Groundwater-Management/SGMA-Groundwater-Management&#34;&gt;California&#39;s Sustainable Groundwater Management Act&lt;/a&gt;, but also general enough to be applied to real-time data from any sensor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cal water quality .com</title>
      <link>https://www.richpauloo.com/project/cwq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.richpauloo.com/project/cwq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Present sources of water quality information in California (i.e. - consumer confidence reports, or CCRs) are fragmented across thousands of water utilities in the state, lack consistency and clarity, and tend to communicate data via hard-to-understand tables (see 3 examples of CCRs below, or view them in their entirely&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.).&lt;/p&gt;













&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;ccrs.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;CCR quality varies by water system.&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;ccrs.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    CCR quality varies by water system.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near-real-time, standardized, and easy to understand water quality reports would improve the public’s understanding of the water they buy and consume. Automated creation of water quality reports would ease reporting responsibilities for water agencies, freeing them to tackle harder problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aimed to build a “weather app” for California community water system water quality. The benefits of this approach include standardization, consistency across agencies, ease of use, and near-real-time water quality information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project aggregates publicly available water quality data for all California community water systems to report:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compliance status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chemicals detected within the past 2 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;average detection levels for all contaminants tested for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;water quality indicators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;local water and health system contact information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.richpauloo.com/files/ccr1.pdf&#34;&gt;CCR example #1&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.richpauloo.com/files/ccr2.pdf&#34;&gt;CCR example #2&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.richpauloo.com/files/ccr3.pdf&#34;&gt;CCR example #3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gsa well failure .com</title>
      <link>https://www.richpauloo.com/project/gwf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.richpauloo.com/project/gwf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About 1.5 million residents of California’s Central Valley rely on private domestic wells for drinking water, and many of these wells can, and oftentimes do, fail during drought or as the result of unsustainable groundwater management. This project uses hydrologic modeling, statistical learning, and data science to predict how groundwater level changes will impact domestic well failure and provides estimated information on drinking water shortages for underserved populations. Decision makers and local agencies can use this information to prevent well failure and inform water resource management and planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View the project &lt;a href=&#34;https://gsawellfailure.com&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, made possible with support from the AI for Earth Innovation Program Grant provided by Global Wildlife Conservation and Microsoft Corporation. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.globalwildlife.org/press/winners-of-ai-for-earth-innovation-grants-poised-to-address-urgent-environmental-challenges-with-creative-use-of-technology/&#34;&gt;See press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactive transport</title>
      <link>https://www.richpauloo.com/project/bgc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.richpauloo.com/project/bgc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sandy beaches, traditionally regarded unreactive due to their low carbon content, were found to be &lt;a href=&#34;https://eos.org/research-spotlights/sandy-beaches-are-hotbeds-of-biochemical-activity&#34;&gt;hotspots of carbon-fueled reactions that can decrease nitrate contamination&lt;/a&gt; in nearshore waters. During waves and tides, seawater delivers particulate organic carbon into the sands that are distributed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JG005114&#34;&gt;complex patterns&lt;/a&gt; and fuels reactions.&lt;/p&gt;













&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;poc_conceptual_model.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Particulate organic carbon (green) in beach systems remove nitrate (solute) from fresh groundwater via contact. As the mixing patterns between fresh groundwater and saline seawater changes with tidal conditions, the location that allows for nitrate removal changes. This shows the location of nitrogen gas (byproduct of nitrate removal) within the beach cross-section as tidal conditions change.&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;poc_conceptual_model.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Particulate organic carbon (green) in beach systems remove nitrate (solute) from fresh groundwater via contact. As the mixing patterns between fresh groundwater and saline seawater changes with tidal conditions, the location that allows for nitrate removal changes. This shows the location of nitrogen gas (byproduct of nitrate removal) within the beach cross-section as tidal conditions change.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this work, we modeled the complex mixing patterns of terrestrial groundwater and seawater, to understand hydrologic controls on reactions between particulate carbon and other solutes (e.g., oxygen, nitrate).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project, for the first time, provided sensitivity analyses for variable-density systems that involve reactions that depend on both particulate and solute reactants. Such analyses are useful as modeling water quality often involves density differences or solid phases of contaminants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related publications include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/2017JG003943&#34;&gt;Beach aquifer reactivity due to mixing of fresh groundwater (FW) and saline seawater (SW)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JG005114&#34;&gt;Complex FW-SW mixing create heterogeneous carbon distributions within beach sands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
